<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Basic HTB and Linux things on Arjen Wiersma</title><link>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/handbook/100_basics/</link><description>Recent content in Basic HTB and Linux things on Arjen Wiersma</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/handbook/100_basics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>🌍 Connecting to the vpn</title><link>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/handbook/100_basics/vpn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/handbook/100_basics/vpn/</guid><description>HTB Documentation: Introduction to lab access.
Hack The Box uses a VPN (Virtual Private Network) to connect the users to the machines. To connect to this network we use a tool called openvpn.
Download the openvpn file. Login to Hack The Box. Click on the &amp;#34;Connect to HTB&amp;#34; button. Select the server you want to connect to, then select OpenVPN. Download the OpenVPN file. Connect with OpenVPN Open the file with openvpn within Kali:</description></item><item><title>Basic Linux Commands</title><link>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/handbook/100_basics/linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/handbook/100_basics/linux/</guid><description> Copy contents of a file to the clipboard The xclip command is very useful when you want to copy files to the clipboard.
sudo apt install xclip Use it as follows to put something on the internal clipboard of your VM:
cat file | xclip -selection clipboard If you want to use it to copy something from you VM to your host machine, use the primary.
cat file | xclip -selection primary</description></item><item><title>🧪 Burp Proxy</title><link>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/handbook/100_basics/burp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/handbook/100_basics/burp/</guid><description>To view and manipulate network traffic to and from websites we often use a tool called Burp Suite.
Viewing traffic with the Proxy To view traffic to and from websites Brup makes acts a so-called &amp;#34;proxy&amp;#34;, acting as a middleman between the browser and webserver. The easiest way to connect through this proxy is by using Burp&amp;#39;s built-in browser. To open this browser head to the Proxy tab, the Intercept tab and click on Open Browser.</description></item></channel></rss>