<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Arjen Wiersma</title><link>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/</link><description>Recent content on Arjen Wiersma</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 16:31:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Open Universiteit: Software Quality Management</title><link>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/posts/ou-sqm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 16:31:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/posts/ou-sqm/</guid><description>Background I have been working on getting my Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Software Engineering. To do this I have started following courses at the Dutch Open Universiteit. They have a Master&amp;rsquo;s program that takes 2 years and you are able to follow it from home.
As this is my first post on the courses, I will give some background. As a teacher it is recommended to have a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree. As I had a whole lot of work experience my teaching activities were not a problem, but from an overall point of view I was advised to pursue an Master degree.</description></item><item><title>Badge Challenge 3</title><link>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/posts/badge-challenge-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 12:10:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/posts/badge-challenge-3/</guid><description>Original Post During each in-person Hack The Box meetup I have a small badge challenge that will give the first solver of the challenge a price. at the meetup of March 2023 there will be a very nice little challenge to be done as well, a beautiful NOVI hoodie. You can already download the password protected zip archive. The password will be shared during the meetup opening words.
The zip archive (sha1: 28e84243c79caefce06f62ba2c5d930de37a3439) Good luck.</description></item><item><title>Deployment Anxiety</title><link>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/posts/deployment-anxiety/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/posts/deployment-anxiety/</guid><description>Let me tell you how it was to ship a product out to half a million people back in 1999. But before I do that, let me tell you why. Today I talked to one of my students and he mentioned that he was very nervous about a change he was making. He was afraid it would break things and that he would spend the afternoon working through his CI/CD pipeline to resolve issues.</description></item><item><title>Cleaning up after LSP-mode</title><link>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/posts/cleaning-up-lsp-mode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/posts/cleaning-up-lsp-mode/</guid><description>I use lsp-mode quite extensively. I switched from eglot when I started using LSP more. The beautify of lsp-mode is that it will automatically install language servers as you need them. It also integrates excellently with dap-mode to enable debugging sessions. So, I switched to it, turned off all the information overload and I am quite happy.
One thing I do extensively is that I use LaTeX to make my slides for college class slides and class assignments.</description></item><item><title>Should we pay for open source?</title><link>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/posts/should-we-pay-for-oss/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/posts/should-we-pay-for-oss/</guid><description>As the world is processing the Twitter deal the open source project Mastodon is gaining a lot of traction. The instance that I am on, fosstodon, is run by a small team and is fully funded by donations.
Now this may sound somewhat strange; as the twitterverse is blowing up about $8/month for a blue checkmark I would argue that the $8 is better spent supporting open source projects. As developers, security people, and users we rely on a lot of free time and effort from open source contributors.</description></item><item><title>22 years of Emacs</title><link>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/posts/22-years-of-emacs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/posts/22-years-of-emacs/</guid><description>Where to begin&amp;hellip; I just watched David Wilson&amp;rsquo;s talk called M-x forever - why Emacs will outlast text editor trends. He gave this talk at EmacsConf 2021 which is a conference dedicated to Emacs. The talk made me reflect on my use of Emacs over the last years and then I realized that this year will mark 22 years that Emacs and I have been together. This (probably too long) article reflects on those years and dives into my use of Emacs.</description></item><item><title>Hack The Box Ambassador</title><link>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/posts/htb-ambassador/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/posts/htb-ambassador/</guid><description>For the last 18 months I have organized the dutch Hack The Box meetups. Due to COVID-19 they have all been as a digital meetup, but not less entertaining though.
During my time organizing the meetups the Hack The Box organization supports me in various ways; they give me stuff to hand out such as swag or VIP memberships, they help organize speakers for events when we don&amp;rsquo;t have one ourselves and they provide me with Hack The Box goodies every once in a while.</description></item></channel></rss>