<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Education on Arjen Wiersma</title><link>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/tags/education/</link><description>Recent content in Education on Arjen Wiersma</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 22:15:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Starting my Master Thesis</title><link>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/posts/starting-master-thesis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 22:15:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/posts/starting-master-thesis/</guid><description>Today, I took the first step towards starting my master&amp;rsquo;s thesis. I have decided to document my journey and experiences on my blog. Given that the thesis will play a pivotal role in my life for the next nine months, I expect it to be a thrilling journey.
Finding a topic As a student at Open Universiteit in The Netherlands, I had the opportunity to work with the Rascal programming language during the Software Quality Management course.</description></item><item><title>Open Universiteit: Software Quality Management</title><link>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/posts/ou-sqm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 16:31:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.arjenwiersma.nl/posts/ou-sqm/</guid><description>Background I have been working on getting my Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Software Engineering. To do this I have started following courses at the Dutch Open Universiteit. They have a Master&amp;rsquo;s program that takes 2 years and you are able to follow it from home.
As this is my first post on the courses, I will give some background. As a teacher it is recommended to have a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree. As I had a whole lot of work experience my teaching activities were not a problem, but from an overall point of view I was advised to pursue an Master degree.</description></item></channel></rss>