<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on Arjen Wiersma</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on Arjen Wiersma</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Arjen Wiersma</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 12:31:17 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Digital Ocean, its support and development database</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/20250126-digital-ocean-dev-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 12:31:17 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/20250126-digital-ocean-dev-database/</guid>
      <description>Tip Currently, only use Postgres 14 on the Digital Ocean application platform for development databases. While following the book Zero2Prod you will learn how to deploy a Rust application to digital ocean through a Continuous Deployment pipeline. This is hardly anything new for me, I even teach a course in DevOps, but to not stray from the path of the book I followed its instructions.&#xA;The spec for digital ocean looks like this (this is abbreviated for your reading pleasure):</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choose your tools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/choose-your-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/choose-your-tools/</guid>
      <description>Note Originally posted on 2024-09-30 (Monday). It was updated in January of 2025. I ❤️ to build software. I sadly do not have a lot of time next to my daily work to spend on my side projects, so I have to be disciplined in where I invest time. I wish I could spend endless amounts of time on exploring new technologies, but sadly I simply do not have that time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Traefik</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/setting-up-traefik/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 12:18:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/setting-up-traefik/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across Traefik. It is a reverse proxy built specifically for services in the cloud. I was searching for a convenient (up-to-date) way to expose my project using a reverse proxy within docker-compose. I used to use nginx for this, but it then requires a generator and an lets encrypt listener (so 3 containers). Traefik only requires a single container and allows you to label your docker containers to apply rules to them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhance testability with selmer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/using-selmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 19:42:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/using-selmer/</guid>
      <description>This is my first article in a series called Rock Solid Software. In it I explore different dimensions of software that does not simply break. You can write good software in any programming language, although some are more suited to a disciplined practice then others, Clojure is definitely in the relaxed space of discipline here.&#xA;Today I am exploring the use of Selmer templates in Clojure. If you have explored Biff at all you will know that all the UI logic works by sending Hiccup through a handler, which will turn into HTML through rum (specifically the wrap-render-rum middleware).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My computing environment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-computing-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 15:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-computing-environment/</guid>
      <description>This is a longer form article. I is relevant as of February 18th 2023. If the circumstances of my environment changes I will try to update this article to reflect the situation. You can find the full source code of my dotfiles on Github.&#xA;I like consistency and simplicity. I do not like to use many different tools to do different things, I rather spend my time learning to use a few tools very well then to follow the hype on the latest trend of tools for something we have been doing forever.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deployment Anxiety</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/deployment-anxiety/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/deployment-anxiety/</guid>
      <description>Let me tell you how it was to ship a product out to half a million people back in 1999. But before I do that, let me tell you why. Today I talked to one of my students and he mentioned that he was very nervous about a change he was making. He was afraid it would break things and that he would spend the afternoon working through his CI/CD pipeline to resolve issues.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
