<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emacs on Arjen Wiersma</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/emacs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Emacs on Arjen Wiersma</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Arjen Wiersma</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Choose your tools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/choose-your-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/choose-your-tools/</guid>
      <description>Note Originally posted on 2024-09-30 (Monday). It was updated in January of 2025. I ❤️ to build software. I sadly do not have a lot of time next to my daily work to spend on my side projects, so I have to be disciplined in where I invest time. I wish I could spend endless amounts of time on exploring new technologies, but sadly I simply do not have that time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My computing environment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-computing-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 15:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-computing-environment/</guid>
      <description>This is a longer form article. I is relevant as of February 18th 2023. If the circumstances of my environment changes I will try to update this article to reflect the situation. You can find the full source code of my dotfiles on Github.&#xA;I like consistency and simplicity. I do not like to use many different tools to do different things, I rather spend my time learning to use a few tools very well then to follow the hype on the latest trend of tools for something we have been doing forever.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 years of Emacs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/22-years-of-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/22-years-of-emacs/</guid>
      <description>Where to begin&amp;hellip; I just watched David Wilson&amp;rsquo;s talk called M-x forever - why Emacs will outlast text editor trends. He gave this talk at EmacsConf 2021 which is a conference dedicated to Emacs. The talk made me reflect on my use of Emacs over the last years and then I realized that this year will mark 22 years that Emacs and I have been together. This (probably too long) article reflects on those years and dives into my use of Emacs.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
