<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Arjen Wiersma</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Arjen Wiersma</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Arjen Wiersma</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>European Union Vulnerability Database</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/euvd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/euvd/</guid>
      <description>The European Union Agency for Cybersecurity (ENISA) has its own Vulnerability Database, called the European Union Vulnerability Database (EUVD). It&amp;rsquo;s datasource is The Vulnerability Lookup project, a system that correlates various sources and streamlines Coordinated Vulnerability Disclosure (CVD). It uses the Global CVE Allocation System (link) as a source. This system is created with funding by the EU and is maintained by Computer Incident Response Center Luxembourg (CIRCL), with a nice dashboard here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developer Growth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/developer-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/developer-growth/</guid>
      <description>Uncle Bob, in his presentations, likes to say that the number of developers in the world doubles every 5 years. Recently The Primeagen in one of his shorts he echos that statement. They both do not give any source for this information, so can it be validated?&#xA;The Netherlands has an agency called Centraal Bureau voor de Statistiek (CBS) which collects all kinds of statistics about the country. It turns out that they also have statistics on the type of field people work in.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Emacs for Clojure development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/clojure-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 20:25:59 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/clojure-emacs/</guid>
      <description>Emacs 🥰 Lisp, and as Clojure is a Lisp like language, Emacs is extremely capable in editing it. I use several packages to make my live a joy inside Emacs, here are the Clojure specific packages:&#xA;paredit: I highly recommend it to work with any lisp, it makes working with the parenthesis a real joy. There is an animated guide of most of the features. cider: The only thing you need to run and work with Clojure files flycheck-clj-kondo: brings the hints from clj-kondo to the editing screen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Clojure programming language</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 22:18:54 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/clojure/</guid>
      <description>The Clojure programming language. It is a functional programming language on top of dthe JVM. It is a Lisp like language.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Emacs for Rust development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/rust-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/rust-emacs/</guid>
      <description>Emacs is great for editing Rust source files. In addition to your normal Emacs configuration (such as completion modes) it requires 3 packages. First you will want lsp-mode, a very full featured LSP client for Emacs. Additionally you will want lsp-ui, which I only use for the lsp-ui-imenu feature.&#xA;Finally you will want to use rustic as primary editing mode for Rust files.&#xA;elisp elisp code snippet start&#xA;;; For all setttings see: https://emacs-lsp.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Rust programming language</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/rust/</guid>
      <description>This is the rust programming language</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Type-Driven Design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/type-driven-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/type-driven-design/</guid>
      <description>Rust has allows for a pattern called Type-Driven Design. In the below example a SubscriberName is created. It has a single String value. In simple code this might be represented as let subscriber_name = &amp;quot;Arjen&amp;quot;.to_string();. By making the type you can wrap the validation logic into the creation of the type. This means that wherever you get a paramter of type SubscriberName you know it is valid.&#xA;rust rust code snippet start</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero to Production</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/zero2prod/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/zero2prod/</guid>
      <description>A book about making production systems in the Rust programming language.&#xA;Website: https://www.zero2prod.com/index.html </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/vibe-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/vibe-coding/</guid>
      <description>Vibe Coding In Beyond Vibe Coding, Addy Osmani defines it like this:&#xA;“In vibe coding, you leverage powerful LLMs as coding partners, letting them handle the heavy lifting of code generation so you can focus on higher-level goals.”&#xA;“On one end of the spectrum lies vibe coding. On the other end is what I’ll call AI-assisted engineering: a disciplined method of weaving AI into each phase of software development, from design through testing, under clear constraints.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
